Now let me give you a quick reminder of the Kalman filter for
ここで 思い出して ほしいのが 単純な 1Dの動きに 使った
a simple 1D motion case.
カルマンフィルターです
Let's say that our mission is to track a pedestrian whose state,
ここでの目標が 歩行者の 追跡で 歩行者の状態xを
x, is described by a position and velocity.
位置と 速度で 表すとしましょう
When designing the Kalman filter, we have to define the two linear functions.
カルマンフィルターを 設計するには 2つの 線形関数を 定義する必要が あります
The state transition function,
一方の 状態遷移関数は
that models how the state is changed from time k-1 to time k.
時点k-1から 時点kの 間での 状態の変化を モデル化します
And the measurement function, that models how the measurement is
他方の 測定関数は 測定の 計算方法と それが
calculated, and how it's related to the predicted state x.
予測された状態xと どのような関係にあるかを モデル化します
The first terms in these functions represent the deterministic part of
これらの関数の 最初の項は モデルの 決定論的な性格を
our model.
形成します
And the last terms, nu noise and omega noise, represent the stochastic part.
そして最後の項である ノイズνと ノイズωは 確率的な部分を 構成します
Or in other words, random noises that affect the prediction and
言い換えると 予測と 測定値更新のステップに 影響を 及ぼす
measurement update steps.
ランダムノイズです
So by using the linear motion model with a constant velocity, the new location,
速度が一定の 線形モーションモデルを 使った場合 歩行者の
p, of our pedestrian is the old location + velocity times delta t.
新しい位置pは 前の位置+速度xΔt となります
Because velocity is constant,
速度が 一定なので
the new velocity is the same as the old velocity.
新しい速度は 前の 速度と 同じです
We can express this in a matrix form like so.
これを 行列形式で 表すと こうなります
And for the measurement function, our vehicle only senses the pedestrian
測定関数については 私たちの 車両は 歩行者の位置だけを
position, so the measurement function looks like this.
検知するので 測定関数は こうなります
It also can be represented in a matrix form as so.
これも 行列形式にすると
As we already know, the Kalman filter algorithm is composed of a prediction
すでに 学んだとおり カルマンフィルターを 構成する 2つのステップは
step where we predict our state and covariance p.
共分散pを 予測する 予測ステップと
And we also use a measurement update step, often called correction step,
最新の測定値を 使って 状態の 推定値と不確かさを
where we use the latest measurement to update the state estimate and
更新する 更新ステップ あるいは
its uncertainty.
修正ステップです